Guide to the Lesbian and Gay Studies Center at Yale Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Lesbian and Gay Studies Center at Yale records
1987-1990
RU 1013
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.75
(2 boxes)
The records consist of meeting minutes, correspondence, newsletters, an annual report, and conference brochures documenting the establishment and activities of the Lesbian and Gay Studies Center at Yale. Also included is a compilation of newscasts (VHS) concerning the protests following the arrest of some participants of the 1989 conference, Inside/Out, sponsered by the center.
Lesbian and Gay Studies Center at Yale
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 37 (YRG 37), Records of associations, institutes, centers, and organizations affiliated with Yale University.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift, 2006.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The records are arranged chronologically.
Biographical / Historical
Established in 1987, the Lesbian and Gay Studies Center at Yale promoted, organized, and desseminated research on the lives and history of lesbians and gay men through conferences, lectures, and a newsletter. The center was founded by Yale faculty and students, but was not administered by Yale University.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of meeting minutes, correspondence, newsletters, an annual report, and conference brochures documenting the establishment and activities of the Lesbian and Gay Studies Center at Yale. Also included is a compilation of newscasts (VHS) concerning the protests following the arrest of some participants of the 1989 conference, Inside/Out, sponsered by the center.
Gay and lesbian studies; Lesbian and Gay Studies Center at Yale
- Records of the Lesbian and Gay Studies Center at Yale, 1987-1990; Accession 2007-A-029
  - Minutes, 1987-1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Annual report, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Poster, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Additional Materials, 1987-1990; Accession 2007-A-085
  - Correspondence -Conferences, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Dobbs incident material, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Material concerning Center courses and resources, 1987-1990 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Material concerning Center tax-exempt status, 1987-1990 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Additional Materials, 1989; Accession 19ND-A-439
  - News coverage, 1989; videotape (VHS) (Box 1)
    - Use copy, videtape (VHS) (Box 1U)